你的纱布在渗血
You're bleeding through your bandage.
早啊
Good morning.
不用去找医生吗
Don't we need to get you to a doctor?
我就是医生
I am a doctor.
昨晚我没提吗
That didn't come up last night?
我们聊的不多
We didn't do a lot of talking.
我没事
I'm good.
你没说过你是如何受伤的
You never told me what caused your accident.
我被个病人捅了
I was stabbed by a patient.
以后收医药费绝不手软
That'll teach me to overbill.
发件人  豪斯
叮咚
如果她喜欢瘸子
If she likes crippled guys,
我倒有六分钟空余时间
I'm free for the next six minutes.
你来做什么
What do you want?
45岁的卡车司机
45-year-old truck driver,
癫痫反复发作
recurrent seizures.
没有代谢和结构上的...
No metabolic or structural--
你觉得现在是时候吗
Does this look like a good time?
算是
Sort of.
至少和过去三周  我12次
At least as good as the other 12 times
打你电话呼你时  情况类似
that I've called and paged you in the last three weeks.
那是我不想和你说话
Those times I just didn't feel like talking to you.
现在也差不多
Kinda like now.
我可以再次道歉
I'd apologize again,
不过上次你还没原谅我
but I'm still waiting for you to accept the first one.
你可是给我打工的
You do work for me.
我有权问  你什么时候上班
I am entitled to ask when you're coming back.
我不知道我什么时候回去
I don't know when I'm coming back.
我不知道我还想不想回去
I don't know if I'm coming back.
你要看不惯
Got a problem with that,
炒了我啊
fire me.
总监：
zlean
做得好
Nice.
在医院看到你真好
It's good to see you in the hospital,
哪怕不是来当医生  当病人也好
as a patient if not as a doctor.
相信我
Believe me,
我宁愿是穿白大褂的
I'd rather be the guy with the clipboard.
你怎么样
How you doing?
不再出现心律失常
Arrhythmias are gone.
精细动作的控制渐好
Fine motor control is improving.
我指的不是那些
Not what I meant.
如果你需要和人谈谈
If you need to talk to someone,
心理咨询
a professional...
我很好
I'm fine.
好到可以上班了吗
Fine enough to get back to work?
你可以不为豪斯工作
You don't have to work for House,
但你欠我20小时的门诊
but you do owe me 20 clinic hours.
怎么  挨了一刀我想放个假都不行
What, getting knifed doesn't buy me an extension?
你想要什么都行
Buys you whatever you need.
但我了解你
But I know you.
如果你只做理疗
If all you do is physical therapy
外加同女人鬼混
and your nighttime version of it,
没等到
you'll lose your mind
能重拾精细动作你就疯掉了
faster than you regain those fine motor skills.
我  我的左肩
I, uh, have this terrible pain
疼得厉害
in my left shoulder.
来得莫名其妙
It came out of nowhere.
用什么办法都不见好
And nothing seems to help.
还有其它症状吗
Any other symptoms?
胸痛  头晕
Chest pain? Lightheadedness?
没有  完全没有
No. None at all.
刚开始疼时你在做什么
What were you doing when the pain came on?
就是坐着祈祷
Just sitting and praying.
那天早上她在帮我做圣饼
She'd been helping to make the altar breads that morning,
但运动量不大  也没反复性动作
but no hard physical work or repetitive motion.
有很多可能
A couple of possibilities.
你的淋巴结肿大
You have enlarged lymph nodes,
我想先排除乳腺癌的可能
so I'd like to start by ruling out breast cancer.
我说的是"排除"
And I do mean "Rule out."
可能并无大碍的
It's probably nothing.
我想做个快速的乳房检查
I'm gonna do a quick breast exam.
你不介意先出去一下吧
Do you mind stepping out for a moment?
不介意
Not at all.
这样我才能就第二种可能发问
That was so I could ask about the second possibility.
左肩痛可能是心绞痛的表现
Left-sided pain means it could be angina,
会因压力而加重
which is made worse by stress.
而与人生中某一剧变
Might not be a coincidence that the pain started
同时出现  也不是碰巧吧
on the verge of a major life change.
你怎么知道
How did you know?
蓝色头巾说明你是预备修女
Blue veil means you're a postulant,
还未发愿
haven't taken your vows yet.
修女经过誓发初愿 复愿 终身愿等过程
表示自己对主的献身
棕色衣着说明你来自加尔默罗会
Brown vestments means you're carmelites,
静修修女
cloistered nuns,
有人监护也与此吻合
which explains the chaperone.
你正打算永离俗世
You're about to withdraw from the world for good.
我曾是神学院学生
I was a seminarian.
显然没发过愿
Who obviously didn't take his vows.
教士服让我臀部显大
Cassock made my ass look fat.
麻烦你解开扣子平躺下来
Do you mind unbuttoning your shirt and lying down for me?
好的
Okay.
我也犹豫过
I have had second thoughts.
我不够虔诚
I'm kind of a wreck.
与世隔绝
A life of perpetual enclosure
远离尘嚣
and almost complete silence?
如果你这都不慎重考虑
If you weren't wrestling with this,
我只能说你肯定不正常
I'd say there's something really wrong with you.
我得坦白和你说
I'm going to admit you.
这有个小的肿块
There's a little mass here,
我想做个详细检查
and I'd like to get it checked out.
只是良性脂肪沉积
It's just a benign fat deposit.
片子没问题
Her imaging's clean.
压力测试也没问题  不是心绞痛
Stress test too. It's not angina.
那为什么会肩痛
So why the shoulder pain?
有没有可能
Is it possible
是她自残
that she hurt her shoulder?
-真要感谢你  -我没告诉他
- Thanks a lot. - I didn't tell him.
你刚才行踪诡秘
You were cagey about where you were going.
奇斯一直小心翼翼
And Chase being cagey in general.
看似有很大机会  在一处逮住你俩
Good chance I'd find the two of you in the same cage.
所以我让朴克尾随其后
So I had Park follow you.
你好点没有
How you feeling?
好多了
Better.
听说你手臂恢复得不错
Heard your arm's healing nicely.
看到你能走动真好
Good to see you on your feet.
病人是修女
Patient's a nun?
遭遇坎坷让你又重拾
You turning back to your long-abandoned faith
早已摒弃的信仰了吗
in time of trouble?
她是我的门诊病人
She was next up in the clinic.
还有  我不需要你帮忙
And I don't want your help.
你被捅了
You got stabbed.
你怪我
You blame me.
但这么多年来
But what did you learn about me
你还不了解我吗
that you hadn't known for years?
也许我以前是傻子  现在不是了
Maybe I was an idiot before and I'm not one now.
也许反过来才是对的
Or maybe the reverse is true.
谢谢你的帮忙
Thanks for all your help.
你的精神伴侣受真菌感染
Your soul sister is having a fungal infection
源于圣饼里未加工的小麦
from the unprocessed wheat in the altar breads.
解释了肩痛及淋巴结肿大
Explains the shoulder pain and the jumbo lymph nodes.
谢谢我的帮忙
Thanks for all my help.
抱歉  我把豪斯带了过来
I'm-- I'm sorry I led House to you.
这是工作的一部分
It's part of the job.
要不下班一起吃个晚饭
Maybe we could get a meal after work tonight,
如果你需要人陪的话
if you want some companionship.
你是在约我吗
You asking me out on a date?
没有
No.
我只是...越描越黑了
I just-- I guess that sounded--
回来肯定有负担的
Must be scary to be back.
手术刀啊  针头啊
All those knives and needles.
放眼到处是受感染的血液和组织
Infected blood and tissue everywhere you look.
只是觉得你需要和人谈谈
Just thought you might need someone to talk to about it.
知道有你关心我  就足够了
Just knowing you're there for me is enough.
谢谢
Thanks.
在季拉海滩冲过浪没
Ever surf Kirra point?
很明显你是澳洲人
Obviously you're australian.
整个黄金海岸我都玩过
I've surfed all over the Gold Coast.
别告诉我你也是
Don't tell me you have.
离我最近的是威美亚湾
The closest I got was Waimea Bay.
我在毛伊岛长大的
I grew up on Maui.
恕我冒昧
If you don't mind me asking,
你为什么要当修女
why are you becoming a nun?
因为我冲浪所以你这么问
You asking 'cause I surf?
虽然我知道耶稣曾水上行走  但
Well, I know that Jesus walked on water but...
况且大多预备修女要比你年轻
Plus the average postulant is a lot younger than you.
你之前是做什么的啊
What were you doing before this?
没什么特别的
Not much of anything.
做做保姆  居无定所
Worked as a nanny. Moved around a lot.
交了几个烂男友  都没成
Bunch of failed relationships.
之后呢
And then what?
上帝与你交流  你听到了上帝的召唤吗
God spoke to you? You heard the calling?
差不多
Something like that.
感知到上帝的存在
Does there have to be some dramatic moment
有必要很戏剧化吗
where the skies part?
一般是的
Usually, yeah.
你进神学院的时候是不是就那样
Is that what happened to you when you entered the seminary?
妈妈酗酒  爸爸不停地工作
Mom drank, dad worked.
把我丢在一个天主教会学校
They stuck me in catholic school.
那些神父和修女就是我的亲人
Priests and nuns were the closest I had to family.
这也不足以让我一辈子当牧师
Turned out that wasn't much of a reason to join the priesthood.
这就是你离开的原因吗
Is that why you left?
差不多
Something like that.
我感觉我快吐了
I think I may throw up.
我到底生什么病了
What's wrong with me?
肯定不是真菌感染
Not a fungal infection.
你可能在想  我为什么要把气球装满汽水
You're probably wondering, why the soda balloons?
没有
I'm not.
那我告诉你
Well, I'll tell you.
你不是第一个
You're not the only one
被人一刀捅进心室后
whose life spiraled out of control
生活就变成一团乱麻的人
when you got knifed in the ventricle.
陶博决定
Taub has decided--
我需要你帮我诊断我的病人
I need help with my patient.
她在呕吐
She's vomiting.
这不是真菌感染造成的
That's not from a fungal infection.
既然你现在不为我工作了
What are you planning to do
你打算怎么办
now that you're not working for me?
我不知道
I have no idea.
一次濒死的经历让我感觉
Almost dying's been clarifying.
我能做任何事
I can do anything.
你能做任何事
You can do anything.
结果你却回到
So you come back to the same building
工作了多年的大楼
you've worked in for years.
我想你该把这条从你的清单上划掉了
Guess you can cross that off your bucket list.
能继续讨论我的病人吗
Can we get to my patient sometime soon?
只要你承认你现在一片迷茫  就没问题
As soon as you admit that you're a confused mess, sure.
你会帮我的
You'll help me,
因为就算你感觉这个病例很无聊
'cause even though you don't find my case interesting,
但你会好奇我那么在意
you find my interest in it interesting.
你要这么说的话
Well, when you put it that way...
胆管炎
Ascending cholangitis.
没打着
Missed me.
不可能  胆红素正常
Can't be, bilirubin's normal.
临床体征会比检查报告快
Clinical signs can show up days before lab signs.
这太好了
This is great.
我们应该经常玩这游戏
We should make this a regular thing.
她的脚没知觉了
She can't feel her foot at all.
这是怎么回事
What does this mean?
这就是说我得多咨询咨询我的同事了
It means I've got to spend more time consulting with a colleague.
17-酮类固醇水平偏低
17-ketosteroid levels are low.
他怎么可能性欲超级旺盛
How can he be hyper-sexual?
你离他更近  他却想舌吻朴克
He tried to tongue-kiss Park when you were closer.
你认为他的性欲正常吗
You think his sexuality is normal?
我需要帮助  我的病人有了新症状
I need more help. My patient has a new symptom.
足部缺血
Ischemic foot.
别在那想怎么损我了
Get the lecture out of your system
我们讨论讨论这个病例吧
so we can talk about my case.
让我先说一则寓言啊
Let me start with an allegory.
好吧  我有点兴趣
Okay, I'm curious.
你对于你被捅的事反应过激
Your overreaction to your stabbing
是为了怪我  即便你很崇拜我
is to blame me even as you are drawn to me.
陶博则选择上笨蛋防身术课程
Taub's is to take moronic self-defense classes.
就那花拳绣腿一点用都没有
That won't defend him against anything.
以色列搏击防身术
Krav maga,
能帮我挡住你的攻击
which helped me block your shot
还能帮我
and will continue to help me
在一个住满嗑药者的楼里
defend myself in a building
保护我自己
full of drugged-up strangers.
陶博应该听从本能和遗传基因
Taub has to accept that by instinct and genetics
承认他是个懦夫
he is a coward,
最适合在出现危险的时候
who's better off running and hiding
逃跑或是躲起来
at the first sign of danger.
我已经一口气挡住了六发彩蛋
I've already fended off six of your blitzkriegs in a row.
那第七个  第八个呢
And the seventh? And the eighth?
第N个呢
And the nth?
就算你打到他了  你能证明什么呢
If you get him, what's that gonna prove?
证明有时会出意外
That unexpected things happen.
就字面上的意思来说
By definition,
没有哪个课会教你预期意外
no class can teach you to expect them.
所以陶博去学那些就是犯傻
Which is why Taub is idiotic to study them,
而你认为那事有多么重要  也是犯傻
and you're idiotic to attach any significance to them.
有血凝块
Blood clot.
她的D-二聚体正常
Her D-dimer's normal.
另外
On the other hand--
如果他说对了血阻
What if he's right about the blockage
但弄错了原因呢
but wrong about the cause?
血管痉挛
Vasospasm.
除了淋巴结  它能解释所有症状
That explains everything but the lymph nodes.
任何小感染都能引起那些淋巴结问题
And any minor infection could have caused those.
给她用钙离子拮抗剂
Calcium channel blocker to treat.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我把手术刀带进病房  差点害死你
I almost got you killed by bringing a scalpel into that room.
我可不好受
I could feel better about that.
但你也救了我的命
You saved my life too.
这就两清了吧
I think the ledger's clear.
但你怎么会没有受到心理伤害呢
But how can you not be traumatized?
因为改变不了已经发生的事实
Can't change what happened.
但能让我今后做出更好的抉择
Can only make better choices from here.
你能说满口大道理
So you're zen about it
但你还生豪斯的气
but won't let go of your anger toward House?
我在咨询心理医生
I'm seeing a trauma counselor.
我觉得你也应该去
I think you should too.
我没事的
I'm okay.
知道有你关心我  就足够了
Just knowing you're there for me is enough.
修道院能让你有这东西吗
Convent lets you have this?
我从一个护士那借的
I borrowed it from one of the nurses.
我现在还只是预备修女
I'm still on temporary vows.
艾米纳姆  美国饶舌歌星
九次获得格莱美奖
这可能是我最后一次听艾米纳姆的歌了
It may be the last time I hear Eminem for a while.
你在用iPod
You're using an iPod.
但我从没见你用过念珠
But I've never seen you use rosary beads.
耶稣哪一天离世
What day did Jesus die?
我知道  一个福音说他已死
I know, one gospel says passover,
另一个说在之前一天
another says the day before.
在彼得第三次否认认识耶稣前
How many times did the cock crow
公鸡一共叫了多少次
before Peter's third denial?
一次还是两次
Once or twice?
信仰不会因你的质疑而改变
You can't argue away my faith.
为什么
Why?
因为就算有矛盾的地方
Because it's so strong
信仰的力量也十分强大
even plain contradictions--
因为它没那么强大
Because it's not that strong.
我不是说我没有信仰
I'm not saying I don't have faith.
我只是还没感受到神启而已
I just haven't felt the calling yet.
人只有感到召唤  才会想成为神职人员
No one joins the clergy without having that epiphany.
切身体会到上帝的博爱
That god's love is speaking to you directly.
我要的是安静  沉思
It's the silence, the contemplation,
生活的秩序
the order.
我需要它们
I need them.
希望其他的圣训之后会来
Hoping everything else will come later.
这不是答案
That's not an answer.
如果你想要安静  带上耳塞就行了
If you want silence, you can get ear plugs.
我见识过外面的世界了
I tried the outside world.
填补不了我的心灵
It wasn't enough.
你结过婚吗
Have you been married?
没有
No.
没孩子  也没事业
No kids. You never found a career.
你好像没怎么见识过外面的世界啊
Doesn't sound like the outside world got much of a try.
而你即将踏入的生活
What you're headed towards now,
是每天安静地祈祷14小时
14 hours a day in silent prayer,
没有家庭
never having a family,
不和别人接触
never touching another human being.
那些是你想要的吧
Just because that's what you'd miss the most.
护士很八卦的
The nurses talk.
及时行乐没什么错
Nothing's wrong with having fun.
他们说你三周前差点死了
They said you were almost killed three weeks ago.
可你紧接着就找乐子去了
You go right back to fun?
这是你当修女的原因吗
Is that why you wanna be a nun?
有人伤了你的心
Someone broke your heart.
没有
No.
我只是在追寻更重要的事
I'm just looking for something more.
我也是
So am I.
我门诊要迟到了
I'm late for work in the clinic.
不是吧
Really?
乔治·华盛贝姆
George Washingbaum?
是《摩登原始人》里的人物
He was a character in the Flintsteins.
我只是在这躲到豪斯离开咖啡厅
Just hiding out till House leaves the cafeteria.
你上的那些自卫课程
The self-defense classes,
觉得学了有什么不一样吗
you think they're making any kind of difference?
倒还不如豪斯的突袭
Not as much as House's surprise attacks.
他的预先谋划  让我也得如此
He thinks three steps ahead, so I do too.
所以你应该接受他的道歉
Which is why you should accept his apology
并回到团队中来
and come back on the team.
他很烦人也很神经
He's annoying, he's maddening.
但他让我们变得更好
But he makes us all better.
了解了
Note to self.
足部颜色良好
Foot color's good.
动脉搏动良好
Arterial pulse is good.
毛细血管再灌注良好
Capillary refill's good.
并且肩膀疼痛也消失了
And her shoulder pain is all gone.
看上去你可以回家了
Looks like you're ready to go home.
我去取车咱们门口见
I'll get the car and meet you out front.
我想说我就在书里
I'd say I'm in the book,
不过从今以后你不会有机会读了
but not the one you'll be reading from now on.
六年前我在火奴鲁鲁当保姆
Six years ago, I was a nanny in Honolulu
照顾一个两岁的可爱小孩
for this beautiful two-year-old boy.
我很爱他
I loved him.
他跟我在一起的时间
Probably spent more time with him
可能比跟他父母都长
than his own parents.
一天我在停车场和别的保姆聊天
One day I was in the park talking with another nanny.
他从沙箱里爬到了大街上
He wandered out of the sandbox into the street,
爬到了行驶中的汽车前
into the path of a moving car.
这可能发生在任何人身上
That could have happened to anyone.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
就算是  他们也会在余生
And even if it did, they'd blame themselves
因此而自责
for the rest of their lives too.
你不应该
You shouldn't.
你不该从本可能幸福的生活中逃离
You shouldn't run from what can still be a good life.
我投奔了上帝
I'm running to god.
在你身上发生了这些事后
After what happened to you,
你不想重新规划你的人生吗
don't you wanna remake your life?
至少我不会逃避
Not by hiding myself away.
希望这对你有所帮助
I hope it works out for you.
其实会很难
It is gonna be hard.
不能和人有所接触
Not touching anyone.
谁能想到圣母的下属居然是个辣妹
Who knew mother inferior was a smoking hottie.
难怪你跟她调情
No wonder you're playing handsies with her.
你觉得我对修女有意思
You think I'm hitting on a nun?
对上帝不满还是我想要挑战
Angry at god or I just need a challenge?
或者你只是害怕和别人关系密切
Or you're terrified of intimacy,
因此你到处留情
which is why you're a serial slut.
不过现在你急于想抓住一只情感的救生艇
But right now you're grasping at an emotional life raft.
那些不可能产生亲密关系的人正是理想人选
Ideally someone for whom intimacy's not an option.
这其实挺有道理的  所以我也不能
That actually makes sense, which I can't say
对你的所做所为妄加评论
about anything else you've been doing.
我没和她有任何感情纠葛
I'm not emotionally involved with her.
虽然我很喜欢听你反驳我
And much as I'd love to hear you contradict me,
不过我七点半在史卡拉歌剧院还有个探索
I have a 7:30 appointment to explore my intimacy issues
亲密关系的约会
at La Scala.
我和这个经纪人聊过  他有点邋遢
I'm talking to this agent. He's a bit of a sleaze.
不过他对于当我的经纪人很兴奋
But he's really excited about representing me.
尽管他现在不能接新客户
Although he can't take on any new clients right now,
不过他正试着替我争取
he's trying to get me an audition
网络肥皂剧的试演
for one of those online soaps.
你以前看过网上的片子吗
Have you ever watched one of those?
我让你觉得无聊了吗
Am I boring you?
很不幸  是这样的
Unfortunately, yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
你不该在这的
You're not supposed to be here.
或是任何地方
Or anywhere.
没错
Yeah.
你是对的
You were right.
我是在逃避
I was running away.
现在你害羞了
Oh, now you're shy.
早上有点亮
It's brighter in the morning.
我们的余生是要在
So are we gonna spend the rest of eternity
被拿木棍的尖尾小恶魔指指点点的
in a lake of fire while pointy-tailed demons
火湖里度过了吗
poke at us with sticks?
这有点吓到我了
This is a little scary for me.
我的一生本来都计划好了
I had a whole life planned.
不是说我没挣扎过
Not that I wasn't struggling with it.
直到我遇见了你
And then I met you.
别担心  我知道你不是那种保持关系的类型
Don't worry, I know you're not the relationship type.
我怎么会不是那种类型
I'm not not the relationship type.
我结过婚的
I was married once.
放松
Relax.
你挺好的
You're fine.
你下一步打算怎么办
So what's next for you?
我得找个地方住下
I have to find a place to live.
找回以前的工作
Get my old job back.
当然  我会感到内疚  开始自我怀疑
Sure, I'll feel guilty, start doubting.
只要你能按一样的方式处理
As long as you keep dealing with your doubts
自我怀疑的问题那...
in the same way then...
莫伊拉
Moira?
不好意思  你刚才说什么了
I'm sorry, did you say something?
你的脖子
Your neck.
怎么了
What?
你是不是耳鸣
Are your ears ringing?
没错
Yeah.
这意味着什么
What does that mean?
我得马上把你送回医院
We've got to get you back to the hospital right away.
将血液送入你大脑的动脉
The artery that's bringing blood to your brain,
发生了破裂
It's coming apart.
意味着你可能中风
Means you could stroke.
我已经通知了最好的医生团队
I've paged a team of our best doctors.
我不像刚才咳嗽得那么厉害了
I don't have to cough as much.
血液凝结了
It's clotted up.
这不好吗
Is that bad?
我们快到了
We're almost there.
告诉我她的血氧含量
Get me her O-two level.
-你在做什么  -我想确保
- What are you doing? - I want to make sure
能把她的手腕放到正确的位置
I can position her wrist properly.
-做什么  -血气分析
- For what? - A.B.G.
我不要血气分析  知道血氧饱和度就好
I don't need an A.B.G. Just get a pulse OX.
我自己来  去拿知情同意书
I'll do it. Grab a consent form.
快去
Go!
我们要马上做手术  好吗
We need to operate right now, okay?
做手术好
Good to operate.
跟我说  这事没有如果  而且  或可是
Repeat this, no ifs, ands, or buts about it.
没有这事  没有如果
No about it and no ifs.
把她送到十一号手术室
Get her into O.R.11.
颈动脉夹层
Carotid dissection,
颈部4英寸的搏动性肿物
four-inch pulsatile mass in her neck,
以及布罗卡氏失语症
and some Broca's aphasia.
一定是有血块
It's got to be a clot
阻止了出血
keeping her from bleeding out.
脉搏
Pulse?
洪脉  四加
Bounding, four-plus.
二十分钟前是三加
It was a three-plus 20 minutes ago.
二十分钟
20?
我以为她刚到
Thought she just got here.
血迹看上去已经干了
That blood looks pretty dry.
刮胡子时割到的吗
Cut yourself shaving?
要知道也可能是
You know, that can happen
修女起床时咳在你身上的
when the nun you woke up with coughs blood on you.
你和修女上床了
You slept with a nun?
修女就罢了  你和病人上床了
Forget nun, you slept with a patient?
前修女以及前病人
Former, to both.
颈内损伤  令人印象深刻
Internal neck trauma, that's impressive.
我以前也碰到过几次
It's happened to me a few times.
来击个掌
Up high.
奇斯医生
Dr. Chase.
血块破裂了
Clot's broken.
送她进去把她鼻子包好
Bring her in and pack her nose.
我需要三号可吸收缝线
I'm gonna need number three vicryls.
我要治好她
I'm gonna fix this.
你不能给她做手术
You're not gonna operate on her.
卡普尔和卡里尔没有空
Kapur and Carlyle are unavailable.
赖利做过的手术远没有我多
Reilly's done far fewer dissections than I have.
赖利和她上床的次数也没有你多
He's also slept with her far fewer times than you have.
你的判断受影响了
Your judgment's compromised.
我和她过夜
I spent the night with her.
并不会影响我怎么下刀
Doesn't change how I make an incision.
你来和他说
Tell him!
去做手术吧
Do the surgery.
你这是不顾病人的安危
You're trying to score points with him
使劲儿讨好他
at the risk of a patient's life.
他手术技术比较好
He's the better surgeon.
动脉夹
Vascular clamp.
你不准备给她做分流吗
You're not gonna put her on bypass?
那个要花半小时准备
It'd take a half hour to set up.
你现在上动脉夹  她会休克的
You clamp now, she could stroke out.
她已经有神经紊乱的症状了
She's already got neurological symptoms.
如果再等三十分钟  会出现大脑损伤的
We wait 30 minutes, she'll definitely have brain damage.
你这么做  她要么完全没事  要么就死亡
You're trying to make sure she's either perfect or dead.
她不会死的
She's not going to die.
如果我能五分钟内完成
If I get this done in five minutes,
她不会休克的
she won't stroke out.
你怎么知道是否来得及
You don't know that you will.
你无法保证因为
And you can't know because you can't
你对她感情用事了
think clearly about her.
动脉夹
Vascular clamp.
闭塞开始时间  九点四十六分二十三秒
Occlusion time 9:46 and 23 seconds.
血管剪
Vascular scissors.
已经超过五分钟了
We're over five minutes.
超声波探头
Ultrasound.
血流良好  减轻麻醉剂量
Good flow. Lighten the anesthesia.
你不先给她缝合吗
You're not gonna close the wound first?
不
No.
你能听见我说话吗
Can you hear me?
跟我说
Repeat this,
没有如果  而且  或可是
no ifs, ands, or buts.
No ifs, ands, or buts.
我对之前的事很抱歉
I'm sorry about before.
你害怕了  是不是
You're scared, aren't you?
所以你才想寻求别人陪伴
That's why you wanted companionship.
所以你在豪斯射击陶博的时候会尖叫
That's why you cried out when House shot at Taub.
你到底有什么好怕的
What exactly are you scared of?
怕被针刺
A needle stick?
还是怕又一个挥舞手术刀的神经病
Some other nut pulling a scalpel?
我啥都怕
I'm scared of everything.
发生了刀刺事件是很不幸
It sucks that there was a stabbing.
但是你会摆脱阴影的
But you'll get over it.
你已经摆脱了吗
Like you have?
你当时压根儿就不在场
You weren't even there.
我知道  我离开了病房
I know, I, I left the room.
我运气好
It was pure luck.
我当时在病房里  也算是种运气吧
I was in the room. That was pure luck too.
你既害怕又感到羞愧  我很理解
I get that you're scared and guilty.
但你是个医生
You're still a doctor.
我可没时间教你怎么当个医生
I don't have time to teach you to act like one.
我们切除了那段动脉
We removed the artery.
发现有结节
I found nodules.
可能是狼疮
Could mean lupus.
抗核抗体阴性
Negative A.N.A.
你上哪儿去
Where are you going?
假装给陶博分派
Great thing about assigning Taub
化验工作的好处就是
fraudulent lab work is you know exactly
能掌握他的动向
where he's gonna end up.
如果装得够假
Great thing about assigning Taub
我们就能欣赏到
obviously fraudulent lab work
他在工作中战战兢兢的表现
is you get to watch his inner paranoiac at work.
然后...
And then...
两枪爆头
Two to the head.
能谈谈我的病人吗
Can we talk about my patient?
你也真不容易
Quite a journey.
前段时间被人戳了心脏
Starts with a surgical tool in your heart
这两天换了你去戳人家小修女
and ends with a surgeon's tool in a nun.
你动什么脑筋
What's the plan?
我想要治好她
Plan's to cure her.
如果这不是毫无意义的滥情
Well, if it's not meaningless sex,
那么就是想从一而终
kinda screams out for an end game.
你就像是追着汽车跑的小狗
You're the dog that's chasing the popemobile.
你确定你想要...
You sure you want...
天啊
Oh, my god.
陶博在盘问清洁工
Taub is interrogating the janitor.
他一定认为我雇了清洁工来袭击他
He must think that I hired him to attack...
对啊  我怎么没想到
Actually, why didn't I do that?
血小板可能被误认为是结节
Plaques could be confused for nodules.
-那可能是...  -梅毒
- Which would mean... - Syphilis.
可以解释肩部和脚的症状
Explains the shoulder and foot involvement.
但愿你用的避孕套
Hope you practiced
天衣无缝
the immaculate contraception.
锁定上膛
Lock and load.
噗呀
Boo-yah!
噗呀你妹
Boo-yah to you too.
但我有几年没过性生活了
But I hadn't had sex in years.
你得的是三期梅毒  说明你患病
Tertiary syphilis means you've had the disease
很长时间了
for at least that long.
这么说你也染上了
Does that mean you also have it?
到了这个阶段可能没有传染性了
Probably not contagious at this point.
这病会导致幻觉吗
Can it cause hallucinations?
不太可能  怎么了
It's unlikely. Why?
我躺在手术台上的时候
While I was on the operating table,
那感觉不像是做梦
it didn't feel like a dream.
我看到那个我照顾过的男孩
I saw the boy who I was caring for.
就是那个车祸死掉的
The one who died.
他走到我跟前
He walked right up to me.
他对你说什么了
What did he say?
他握着我的手
He just held my hand.
好像宽恕我了
It was like he forgave me.
你觉得这事儿玄乎吧
Do you think that's crazy?
我认为你应该从中得到安慰
I think it should give you solace,
从这件事中走出来
help you to move on.
你和你的病人上床了
You slept with your patient?
这个病例你别管了
You're off the case.
是我让她免于大脑损伤
I saved her from brain damage.
你觉得我的判断受影响了吗
You think my judgment's the least bit compromised?
她还在生病
She's still sick.
如果她死了  我们又会面临
If she dies, we'll be in the middle
新一轮的调查
of a brand-new investigation.
你就关心你自己的位子
This is about you covering your own ass.
我给过你时间  对你忍让
I gave you time, leeway,
而你就这么为所欲为
and you decided to do whatever the hell you wanted.
豪斯置规则于不顾
House can dance all over the rules,
导致我被刺  你却对他网开一面
gets me knifed, and he gets a pass.
我才犯了一条错  没人因此受伤
I break a rule, no one gets hurt,
你却要把我调离
but you kick me off my own case?
很不幸  确实如此
Unfortunately, yes.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
是我为你挡了那刀
I took that scalpel for you.
所以我才这么做
That's why I did this.
三周之前的你
Three weeks ago,
绝不会和病人上床
you never would have slept with a patient.
之后也绝不会为她做手术
And you never would have operated on her after.
你需要帮助
You need help.
我需要离豪斯远点
I need to get away from House
离那些能让我回想起他的事物远点
and everything that reminds me of him.
你就是通过不顾他人劝告
By breaking the rules,
违反规则来做到吗
not caring what anyone else thinks.
你就是通过变得和豪斯一样来远离他吗
You're gonna get away from him by turning into him?
好疼啊
It hurts.
右上腹胀痛
Right upper quadrant, pain and distension.
我的胃怎么了
What's wrong with my stomach?
胃没事
Nothing.
是肝脏出问题
This is your liver.
肝衰竭可能由
The liver failure could be
术中低血压诱发
from intraoperative hypotension.
检查了麻醉表
Checked the anesthesia sheet,
血压一直正常
pressure was fine throughout.
是血栓吗
Thrombus?
这个回荡在大厅里
That voice in the hall that none of us
我们完全可以忽略的声音
have any reason to be listening to
倒还有些道理
is not surprisingly wrong.
腹部B超未见异常
Abdominal ultrasound was negative.
只能认为肝脏衰竭
Then we have to assume liver failure
也只是她的症状之一
is just another symptom of whatever she's got.
特鲁索综合症
Trousseau's syndrome could send clots,
导致足部缺血
cause the ischemic foot.
加上淋巴结增大  巨红细胞症
Add the enlarged lymph node, macrocytosis.
播散型T细胞淋巴瘤
Disseminated T-cell lymphoma.
威尔森说不是癌症
Wilson said it wasn't cancer.
威尔森说不是乳腺癌
Wilson says it's not breast cancer.
结节病
Sarcoidosis.
ACE水平正常
Normal ACE level.
与结节病没有必然关系
Highly insensitive for sarcoid.
胸透结果阴性
Negative chest X-rays aren't.
那么只能做活检了
Then we've got to biopsy.
是啊  福曼显然是错误的
Yeah, Foreman's clearly wrong.
你显然不是在抓救命稻草
You're clearly not grasping at straws
因为你显然没有掺杂进个人感情
'cause you're clearly not emotionally involved.
我知道你想要相信她患的是可治疾病
I know you want to believe that this is something we can cure.
可惜不是
It's not.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
多久才能知道是不是癌症
How soon will they know if it's cancer?
几小时内
Within hours.
如果是怎么办
And if it is?
总还可以化疗
There's always chemo.
你说的像是不会管用的样子
You say that like it's not gonna work.
可以延长你的生命
Could extend your life.
几年吗
Years?
只要你需要  我会一直陪在你身边
I'll be here as much as you need.
你还没告诉我你为什么离开修道院
You still never told me why you left the seminary.
玛莉·劳勒
Mary Knoller.
场地管理员的老婆
Wife of the groundskeeper.
被捉个正着  打了一耙子
He caught me with her, got me with a rake.
我屁股上的疤你可能注意到了
Those scars on my ass you may have noticed.
为什么之前不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me that before?
因为这原因太浅薄
Because it was so shallow.
我的离开并不是因为
I wasn't exactly wrestling
大是大非的斗争
with great theological questions.
我不相信
I don't believe that.
你内心一定在挣扎修道院是不是自己的归属
You don't sleep with the groundskeeper's wife,
否则不会和场地管理员的老婆上床
wot unless you're struggling with whether you belong there.
我一直想要相信
I always wanted to believe.
那样我的生活会轻松很多
Would have made my life a lot easier.
可最终还是没有
It never took.
也并不是...
Doesn't...
说...
mean...
来不及
it's too late.
你感到讲话困难吗  像之前那样
Are you having trouble talking, like before?
我能说得出话
I can get the words out.
可是感觉非常累
Just feels heavy when I do.
哪里累
Where?
咀嚼肌这里
Wherever my chewing muscles are.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
豪斯还是偷袭到你了
House finally got you.
-他有千条妙计  我有...  -我有急事
- He tried but-- - I gotta go.
你在场就好了  堪称完美
You shoulda seen it. It was perfect.
她出现了颌跛行
She has jaw claudication.
只要颌跛行与颈动脉内膜剥脱同时出现
If you only heard claudication and carotid dissection...
就一定是巨细胞动脉炎
I'd say giant cell arteritis.
然后吩咐你的前同事们
And I'd tell your former teammates
给她用激素
to put her on steroids.
她可以活下来
She's gonna live.
没错
Yeah.
可是然后呢
And then what?
他们说我的肝功能有起色
They say my liver function's better.
我很快就可以出院了
That I can get out of here soon.
等你出院
And when you do,
我带你去波多黎各埃斯孔迪多
I'm gonna take you to Puerto Escondido.
墨西哥
Mexico?
墨西哥管浪
The Mexican pipeline.
五月初才是冲浪旺季  不过...
Early May is when the surf really picks up but--
怎么了
What's wrong?
我跟院长谈过了
I spoke to the prioress.
你要回修道院
You're going back?
我感受到了召唤
I felt the calling.
因为你看到那男孩
When you saw the boy.
我感到了神的爱  神的荣耀
I felt god's love, his grace.
我一生都在等待这一刻
I've been waiting my entire life for that.
那不是真的
It's not real.
我知道你濒死时没有任何感觉
I know you didn't feel anything when you almost died.
我有
I did.
你感到的是缺氧
You felt oxygen depravation.
你感到的是大脑分泌的去甲肾上腺素
You felt your brain releasing noradrenaline.
你之前没这样说
You didn't say that before.
我当时希望你能放下负担
I wanted you to move on with your life.
我想赞同你
I wanted to reassure you.
我想让你宽心
I wanted you to feel better.
你现在不想了吗
And now you don't?
现在
Now...
我想我爱上你了
I think I love you.
"去甲肾上腺素与濒死体验"
"Noradrenaline and near-death experiences."
我的天哪
Oh, dear.
你看到上帝了
You saw god?
是她看到了
She did.
她想回去修道院
She wants to go back to the monastery.
所以你正在准备一份报告材料
So now you're preparing a powerpoint presentation
让她留在人间与你共享凡俗之乐
to keep her in your garden of earthly delights.
你真是白痴
You're an idiot.
因为我找到了爱人
Because I found someone I love?
因为你是白痴
Because you're an idiot.
至少这一点上你俩很像
At least you two have that in common.
她的感受不过是种化学反应
Her feelings are based on a chemical process.
迟早会消退的
They're gonna wear off.
你刚和她上过床
You just slept with her.
大脑都被催产素占领了
Your brain is exploding with oxytocin.
你以为你的感情就经得起岁月考验
You think that's gonna last through the ages?
她在为盲目的信仰
She's throwing away her life
放弃自己的生活
because of blind faith.
你也一样
So are you!
她找到了她想要的
She's found something
生活的中心和意义
she wants to build her life around.
全然的幻觉  可她显然
It's a total illusion, but apparently she'll take
会喜乐安宁毫不介意
a little ignorance with her bliss.
你要夺走这一切吗
And you want to take that away?
把事实真相强加于人
How many times have you thrown the truth
不是你最常做的事情吗
in people's faces?
我是为了事实真相
Because it's the truth,
不是为了和人家百年好合
not because we're gonna live happily ever after.
只有两种可能
Either your relationship just blows up
你俩像所有非童话浪漫一样告吹
like every other non-magical romance,
或者她留下来  一辈子都怨你
or she stays with you but blames you
毁掉了她生命的意义
for stripping all the meaning out of her life.
这与真相无关
This has nothing to do with the truth.
我在重整生活  而你不高兴
You don't like that I'm reassessing my life,
只要我愿意改变
that I want to change it,
我就可以做到
that I can.
谁都可以把自己的生活搞得一团糟
Anyone can screw up a life.
我可没说那是不可能的任务
I never said that wasn't possible.
你自己无法与人亲近
You're incapable of human connection,
想要所有人都像你
so you want everyone to be like you.
如果我想让你和我一样
If I wanted you to be like me...
我就该催促你
I would be urging you
做出这愚不可及的决定
to make a stupid, stubborn decision
毁掉你的一生  让你孤单痛苦
that blows up your life and leaves you lonely and miserable.
做了错事的人才需要重整人生
You reassess your life when you've made mistakes.
你没犯错  你只是被扎了一刀
You didn't. You just got stabbed.
别看书
Don't look at the book.
我从驻院以来都没有做过颈静脉置管
I haven't done a jugular line since my residency.
我不想穿到颈动脉
I don't want to needle the carotid.
第一步是什么
What's the first step?
触诊胸锁乳突肌
Palpate the S.C.M.
在哪里
Where?
颈部的中三分之一
Middle third of the neck.
能认识你我很高兴
I'm happy I knew you.
我也一样
So am I.
罗伯特
Robert.
24岁的水处理工人
24-year-old water treatment worker
发热伴复视
with pyrexia and double vision.
脓肿
Abscess?
磁共振会有显示
Would have seen it on the MRI.
白喉所致眼肌瘫痪
Diphtheria paralyzing the ocular muscles?
不对  首先出现麻痹
No, paralysis was first.
-动脉瘤  -不会伴发热
- Aneurysm? - Not with this fever.
或许是我们考虑的方向不对
Maybe we're thinking about this the wrong way.